A Guide to the Singleton P. Moorehead Papers, 1923-1972
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Singleton P. Moorehead Papers, 1923-1972
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 1989.23
7 cubic ft.
This collection was gathered during the career of Colonial Williamsburg architect, Singleton P. Moorehead (1900-1964), starting from his days as a student at Harvard. It contains architectural drawings, notebooks, notes, sketches, and other illustrations in ten boxes.
Moorehead, Singleton P. (Singleton Peabody) (1900-1964)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Biographical Information
Singleton P. Moorehead (1900-1964) was a prominent Architect involved in the restoration of Colonial Williamsburg. He graduated from Harvard School of Architecture and was a member of the Boston firm Perry, Shaw, and Hepburn when they were involved in the early stages of the restoration project. He was hired directly and worked on the restoration in the town for 35 years, partnering with archeologists to conduct research on historical architecture all around Virginia. He authored multiple reports on the various historic buildings in Williamsburg. In 1944 he became the Head of Architecture and moved to a consulting position in 1948. In 1963 he retired citing poor heath and died a year later.
Scope and Content
This collection was gathered during the career of Colonial Williamsburg architect, Singleton P. Moorehead (1900-1964). Included are finished drawings, sketches, reproductions, artwork, postcards, correspondence, printed material and oversized architectural drawings. Much of the material relates to Williamsburg or Virginia buildings. The bulk of the collection is reference and research material from the reconstruction of Colonial Williamsburg. Also included are materials from when Singleton P. Moorehead (1900-1964) was a student at Harvard, and his time spent studying in Europe, including reproductions of European art and personal original art. There is one item in the collection from after Moorehead's death, a letter sent to a family member located in box six. The majority of the collection is not dated.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in ten boxes, the first five of which are oversized materials. Boxes 1 and 2 are research and reference drawings organized by location name. Box 3 contains his notebooks. Boxes 4 and 5 primarily contain materials from when Moorehead was a student. Box 6 contains correspondence and other miscellaneous reference material. Boxes 7-10 contain reference index cards.
Index Terms
Persons:
Moorehead, Singleton P., 1900-1964.
Subjects:
Architecture, Colonial--Virginia--Williamsburg.; Architecture, Modern.; Architecture--Conservation and restoration--Virginia--Williamsburg.; Architects--Virginia.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Buildings, structures, etc.; Williamsburg--Restoration.
Contents List
- 1, 70 Folders (426 items) (Box 1)
  A collection of reference sketches and elevations signed by Singlton P. Moorehead of various historic buildings around Virginia created in his research of Colonial Virginian architecture. Some of the elevations include whole buildings or a layout of buildings, while others are of fine details. A large number of the items are Photostat black print copies from his sketchbook of architectural details. There is also a number of Cyanotype blueprints of the reference elevations, as well as regular copies of those elevations. Not all of the reference drawings are created by Moorehead, occasionally he notes that he copyed the image from a photograph or book, and some elevations are copied with consent from detailed drawings by W. M. Macomper. Contains field drawings, elavations of architectural details, and photo-reproductions of many elevations and sketches. As well as 9 loose photostats of decrotive interior details.
  - ABINGTON CHURCH GLOUCESTER Co., 2 items (Folder 1)
    Contains sketches with notes with photostat.
  - ABINGTON GLEBE, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 4 items (Folder 2)
    Contains elevations on tissue paper in graphite and a photostat.
  - ALEXANDRIA, VA, 4 items (Folder 3)
    Contains photostats of sketches with notes from folder 1 of abington church.
  - BACON'S CASTLE, SURRY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 4)
    Contatins elevation of details on tissue paper in graphite with photostat of same.
  - PROPOSED BAGBY HOUSE JAMESTOWN, JAMES CITY COUNTY 1933, 5 items (Folder 5)
    Contains elevations on tissue paper in graphite.
  - BELLE AIR CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 6)
    Contains detail sketches with notes with photostat of same.
  - BELLE FARM, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 12 items (Folder 7)
    Contains wooden Door and railing studies with photograph and notes.
  - BOWMAN'S FOLLY, ACCOMACK Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 8)
    Contains drawings on tissue paper with photostat black copies.
  - BROOKE'S BANK, ESSEX Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 9)
    Contains blueprints of elevations and copy of same.
  - CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 10)
    Contains photostats taken from the Sketchbook of architectural details from box 3.
  - CHEALSEA, KING WILLIAM Co., 19 items (Folder 11)
    Contains drawings of woodwork and window details with notes.
  - CHRIST CHURCH, LANCASTER Co. VA, 5 items (Folder 12)
    Contains photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - CLAREMONT, SURRY Co. VA, 5 items (Folder 13)
    Contains sketches and notes.
  - COLE HOUSE JAMES CITY Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 14)
    Contains photostat of reference sketch.
  - CRISS CROSS, NEW KENT Co. VA, 7 items (Folder 15)
    Contains elevations on tissue paper in graphite, notes, and photostat black copies.
  - CUSTIS HOUSE, LEE HALL, NEWPORT NEWS VA, 2 items (Folder 16)
    Contains reference sketch with photostat of same.
  - CUSTOM HSE, YORKTOWN VA (also known as Ambler Store), 2 items (Folder 17)
  - EASTOVER, SURRY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 18)
    Contains reference sketches and notes.
  - FERRIS HOUSE, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 6 items (Folder 19)
    Contains sketches and notes with drawings of molding and other woodwork details.
  - FERRY MANSION, Virginia Beach VA, 2 items (Folder 20)
    Contains blueprint and photostat of estate layout.
  - FOSTER'S CASTLE, NEW KENT Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 21)
    Contains reference drawings tissue.
  - FREDERICKSBURG, SPOTSYLVANIA Co., 1 items (Folder 22)
    Contains photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - GOOCHLAND COURTHSE, GOOCHLAND Co. VA 1929, 2 items (Folder 23)
    Contains reference sketch and layout.
  - GREENWAY, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 9 items (Folder 24)
    Contains drawings of detailed woodwork on mantles, sketches with notes, and photostats of each.
  - HARMONY HALL, FREDERICK Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 25)
  - KIMBROUGH RESIDENCE, NORFOLK VA 1939, 8 items (Folder 26)
    Contains reference sketches with notes and elevations on tracing paper in graphite.
  - KINGSMILL SLAVE QUARTER, JAMES CITY Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 27)
    Contains reference sketches with notes.
  - KING WILLIAM COURTHOUSE, KING WILLIAM Co. VA 1929, 2 items (Folder 28)
    Contains reference layout with sketches and a photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - KITTEWAN, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 11 items (Folder 29)
    Contains drawings of fine woodwork details such as mantles, reference sketches with notes, and photostat of the drawings.
  - LIGHTFOOT LAW OFFICE, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 30)
    Contains a photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - LITTLE ENGLAND, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 20 items (Folder 31)
    Contains drawings of fine woodwork details such as molding and mantles, sketches with notes, and photostat of the drawings.
  - LONDON BRIDGE, VIRGINIA BEACH VA, 9 items (Folder 32)
    Contains drawings of fine woodwork such as moldings and mantles, sketches with notes, and blueprints and photostats of drawings.
  - LOWER BRANDON, PRINCE GEORGE Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 33)
  - LOWER WEYANOKE, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 14 items (Folder 34)
    Contains reference sketches, drawing of wooden staircase, and blueprints and photostats of copies.
  - MANSFIELD, PETERSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 35)
    Contains sketch with notes of buildings.
  - MAPSICO CHURCH, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 36)
    Contains reference sketches with notes with photostat of same.
  - MERCHANT HOUSE, DUMFRIES, PRINCE WILLIAM Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 37)
    Contains sketch with notes.
  - MOUNT AIRY STABLE, RICHMOND Co. VA, 4 items (Folder 38)
    Contains reference sketches with photostats of same and from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - MOUNT PROSPECT, ESSEX Co. VA, 12 items (Folder 39)
    Contains sketches with notes, drawings of molding and mantles, photostats and photocopies of the drawings.
  - MOUNT VERNON, FAIRFAX Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 40)
    Contains sketches with notes and photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - POPLAR FOREST, BEDFORD Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 41)
    Contains Reference sketches with notes and photostats.
  - POPLAR GROVE, MATTHEWS Co. VA, 16 items (Folder 42)
    Contains sketches with notes, drawings of mantle and molding details, and photostats of drawings.
  - PORT ROYAL, CAROLINE Co. VA, 6 items (Folder 43)
  - PROVIDENCE FORGE, NEW KENT Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 44)
    Contains sketches with notes and photostats.
  - RICHARDSON HOUSE, CROKER, JAMES CITY Co. VA, 10 items (Folder 45)
    Contains sketches with notes, drawings of staircase woodwork and mantles, and photostats of the drawings.
  - ROSEWELL, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 46)
    Contains sketch of floor plan with notes.
  - SHIRLEY CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 47)
  - SMITH'S FORT PLANTATION, SURRY Co., 2 items (Folder 48)
    Contains drawings of molding (copied from W.M. Macomber with consent). and photostat of drawing.
  - SOUTHAMPTON COUNTY, 1 item (Folder 49)
    Contains drawing of small exterior building.
  - STRATFORD, WESTMORELAND Co. VA, 1 items (Folder 50)
    Contains notes.
  - SUFFOLK Co., 2 items (Folder 51)
    Contains sketches with notes of Dairy.
  - TABB HOUSE, YORK Co. VA, 1 items (Folder 52)
  - TOANO, JAMES CITY Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 53)
    Contains sketch.
  - TODDSBURY, GLOUCESTER Co. VA, 21 items (Folder 54)
    Contains drawings of interior paneling, molding, mantles and other fine details with blueprints and photostats of those drawings. As well as sketches with notes and photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - TOMAHUND, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 4 items (Folder 55)
  - TOWLE'S POINT, LANCASTER Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 56)
  - TUCKAHOE, GOOCHLAND Co. VA 1929, 3 items (Folder 57)
    Contains copy of the layout of the estate with sketches and photostats.
  - UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA, CHARLOTTESVILLE VA, 2 items (Folder 58)
    Contains sketches with notes and a photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - WALNUT VALLEY, SURRY Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 59)
    Contains drawings on tracing paper of staircase and railings with a photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - WARM SPRINGS, BATH Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 60)
    Contains Sketches with notes and photostats.
  - WELL HOUSES, HANOVER Co. VA, 3 items (Folder 61)
    Contains sketches with notes.
  - WEYANOTE, CHARLES CITY Co. VA, 27 items (Folder 62)
    Contains drawings of woodwork details and sketches with notes. As well as photostats and blueprints of drawings.
  - WILTON-ON-THE-JAMES, RICHMOND VA, 63 items (Folder 63)
    Contains drawing of detailed woodwork and sketches with notes. As well as blueprints and photostats of drawings.
  - WILTON-ON-THE-PIANKATAUK, MIDDLESEX Co. VA, 21 items (Folder 64)
    Contains Drawings of decrotive details and sketches with notes.
  - WISHART HOUSE also known as LYNNHAVEN HOUSE, VIRGINIA BEACH, 2 items (Folder 65)
  - WOODLANDS, GOOCHLAND Co. VA, 4 items (Folder 66)
    Contains drawings of interior woodwork details.
  - WYNNE, JAMES CITY Co. VA, 2 items (Folder 67)
    Contains sketches with notes and a photostat.
  - YORKTOWN, YORK Co. VA, 1 item (Folder 68)
    Cotains a photostat from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
  - MISCELLANEUS DETAILS AND NOTES, 5 items (Folder 69)
    Contains notes regarding research status for the reconstruction.
  - UNIDENTIFIED LOCATION, 3 items (Folder 70)
- 2, 67 Folders (234 items) (Box 2)
  Arranged into two parts, 55 folders in first part and 12 in second. Sketches, notes, and photostats dealing with architectural details around Williamsburg and outside of it respectively. A mix of reference and research material arranged by location. Most of the Photostat black prints are taken from S. Mooreheads Sketchbook of Architectural Details located in Box 3.
  - Historic buildings within Williamsburg, 55 folders (Folder 1)
    Contains reference and research drawings and notes on 18th century buildings within Williamsburg, VA. Also contains some sketches on Native american villages and a sketchbook. Arranged alphebetically by location name.
    - ASCOUGH SHOP also known as MAYO HOUSE AND BOURBOBN HOUSE, 4 items (Folder 1)
      Contains photostats and sketch of miscellaneus architectural details.
    - AYER'S GARAGE also known as PERSON'S GARAGE BIR23, BLDG 16B, 5 items (Folder 2)
      Contains sketches and elevation of floorplan with notes.
    - BASSETT HALL, WMSBURG, 5 items (Folder 3)
      Contains sketched elevations with notes and a photostat of hinge details.
    - BATH HOUSE, WILLIAMSBURG INN, WMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 4)
    - BEECROFT E. BULL, BLOCK 15, BUILDING 32A, SHOP 10, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 2 items (Folder 5)
      Contains sketches of floorplans.
    - BLAIR HOUSE, WMSBURG, 5 items (Folder 6)
      Contains a painted mockup of various houses with floorplans, photostats, and notes.
    - BRICK HOUSE TAVERN, WMSBURG, 1 item (Folder 7)
      Contains a reference sketch.
    - BRUSH-EVERARD HSE, WMSBURG VA, 10 items (Folder 8)
      Contains drawings of architectural details with notes.
    - BRUTON PARISH CHURCH, WMSBURG VA, 5 items (Folder 9)
      Contains photostats.
    - BRUTON PARISH HOUSE, WMSBURG, 2 items (Folder 10)
    - CAPITOL, WMSBURG 1936, 4 items (Folder 11)
    - CARTER'S GROVE, WMSBURG, 1 item (Folder 12)
    - CARTER-ROBERT HOUSE also known as SAUNDERS-DINWIDDIE WILL, 4 items (Folder 13)
      Contains sketches and photostat of architectural details with notes.
    - CASEY HOUSE, WMSBURG, 2 items (Folder 14)
    - CASEY STORE, WMSBURG 1938, 5 items (Folder 15)
      Contains references sketches and notes.
    - CHARLSTON/CHARLETON HOUSE, WILLIAMSBURG, 1 items (Folder 16)
    - CHOWNING'S TAVERN, WMSBURG, 4 items (Folder 17)
    - CLARK HOUSE, WMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 18)
    - COKE GARRETT HOUSE, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 2 items (Folder 18A)
      Contains drawing of wooden gate and a photostat. Likely added to the collection at a later date.
    - COLLEGE OF WILLIAM AND MARY, WMSBURG VA 1936, 3 items (Folder 19)
      Contains sketches of entrance and arches.
    - CRAFT HOUSE, WMSBURG 1937, 2 items (Folder 20)
    - CRAIG POWELL PROPERTY, WMSBURG VA 1935, 1 item (Folder 21)
    - DEANE, ELKANAH FORGE, WMSBURG VA 1944, 2 items (Folder 22)
    - FINNIE, WILLIAMS HOUSE also known as SEMPLE HOUSE, WMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 23)
    - GALT HOUSE, WMSBURG 1944, 3 items (Folder 24)
      Contains sketches with notes of fine details.
    - GOODWIN BLDG, WMSBURG 1936, 3 items (Folder 25)
    - GOVERNOR'S PALACE, WMSBURG 1934-1939, 18 items (Folder 26)
      Contains sketches with notes, report summeries with corrections, and photostats.
    - HUNTER SHOP also known as KINAMON SHOP, WMSBURG 1934, 2 items (Folder 27)
      Contains sketches.
    - KIRBY HSE, WMSBURG, 1 item (Folder 28)
      Contains a sketch of architectural details.
    - LUDWELL-PARADISE HOUSE, WMSBURG 1934-1937, 4 items (Folder 29)
    - MAGAZINE, WMSBURG VA 1954, 2 items (Folder 30)
    - MARKET SQUARE TAVERN, WMSBURG VA, 2 items (Folder 31)
    - MOODY HOUSE, WMSBG VA, 1 items (Folder 32)
      Contains a sketch.
    - NICHOLSON HOUSE, WMSBURG, 1 item (Folder 33)
    - ORRELL HSE, WSMBG VA 1936, 3 items (Folder 34)
      Contains notes, a drawing of a fireplace mantle, and a photostat of the drawing.
    - PALMER HOUSE also known as VEST HOUSE 1934, 5 items (Folder 35)
      Contains reference sketches.
    - PENNINSULA HARDWARE SHOP#3 BLOCK 15, WILLIAMSBURG VA 1938, 1 item (Folder 36)
    - POWELL-HALLAM HOUSE, WMSBURG, 2 items (Folder 37)
      Contains watercolor of houses from each side with floor plan and copy.
    - PRENTIS HOUSE, WMSBURG VA 1937, 3 items (Folder 38)
    - PUBLIC GAOL, WMSBURG 1937, 4 items (Folder 40)
      Contains floorplans and other sketches.
    - RALEIGH TAVERN, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 41)
    - RANDOLPH HOUSE, WMSBG VA, 12 items (Folder 42)
      Contains drawings of interior woodwork details, notes, and photostats.
    - ROBERTS PROPERTY, WMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 43)
    - TALIAFERRO-COLE HOUSE, WMSBURG, 1 item (Folder 44)
    - TAYLOE also known as COLEMAN OFFICE, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 45)
    - TRAVIS HOUSE, WMSBURG 1936-1937, 9 items (Folder 46)
    - TUCKER HOUSE, WMSBG VA 1934, 4 items (Folder 47)
      Contains drawings and sketches of molding styles with photostats.
    - VANGARRETT HOUSE also known as GRISSELL HAY TENEMENT, WILLIAMSBURG VA, 1 item (Folder 48)
    - WALLACE SHOPS BLK 15 BLDG 36A, WMSBURG 1942, 3 items (Folder 49)
      Contains sketches with 2 by J. B. Reed.
    - WILLIAMSBURG INN, WMSBURG 1935-1945, 13 items (Folder 50)
      Contains drawings and sketches of interior wookwork details.
    - WILLIAMSBURG LODGE, WILLIAMSBURG VA 1943, 1 item (Folder 51)
      Contains reference notes.
    - WILLIAMSBURG THEATRE, WILLIAMSBURG VA 1936, 1 item (Folder 52)
    - WYTHE HSE, WMSBG VA, 6 items (Folder 53)
      Contains sketches and drawings of staircase details. As well as photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
    - MISC. WMSBG DETAILS 1936-1946, 18 items (Folder 54)
      Contains sketches with notes, photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details, and a photograph of the town's layout circa 1786.
  - Historic buildings outside of Virginia, 12 folders (Folder 2)
    Contains reference and research drawings and notes on colonial style architecture outside of Virginia. Arranged alphebetically by location name.
    - BACHELOR'S HOUSE, MARYLAND, 1 item (Folder 1)
    - DELAWARE, 3 items (Folder 2)
      Contains reference sketches and photostats.
    - ENGLAND 1941, 3 items (Folder 3)
      Contains plate from Perry, Shaw, and Hepburn of staircase details. As well as some reference sketches.
    - FARMINGTON, CONNECTICUT, 1 item (Folder 4)
      Contains a reference sketches.
    - FRANCE, 3 items (Folder 5)
      Contains drawings of interior details.
    - MCKAY HOUSE, MARYLAND, 2 items (Folder 6)
      Contains sketches and a photostat.
    - MILLS POINT, CHARLES COUNTY, MARYLAND, 4 items (Folder 7)
      Contains sketches and photostats from the Sketchbook of architectural details.
    - NANTUCKET, MASSACHUSETTS 1937, 2 items (Folder 8)
      Contains reference sketches with a photostat.
    - NEW CAANAN, CONNECTICUT, 1 item (Folder 9)
    - SELDEN HOUSE, ANDOVER, MASSACHUSETTS, 7 items (Folder 10)
      Contains sketches of floorplans with notes.
    - WANTWATER, PRINCE GEORGE'S CO., MD, 3 items (Folder 11)
    - VANDERVEER FARM, FLATBUSH, LONG ISLAND, 1 item (Folder 12)
- 3, 27 Notebooks (Box 3)
  Contains Moorehead's notebook from his student trips to Europe through his professional career working on the restoration of Colonial Williamsburg. Most notebooks contain reference notes and sketches that pretain to his architectural career while working on the restoration of Colonial Williamsburg, most undated. Includes the Sketchbook of architectural details which serves as the source to many photostats from boxes 1 and 2. While many of the notebooks are numbered, they do not appear to have been numbered by the creater and they are not arranged in numerical order. Not all notebooks are full and many have leaves removed. The notebooks are not arranged in any clear order, and stored flat in an oversized box.
  - Sketchbook of architecural details, 152 pages (31 cm) (Volume 1)
    A collection of reference drawings of milwork and other fine architectural details. The source of many of the photostats in boxes 1 and 2.
  - Field notebook, 92 pages (26 cm) (Volume 2)
    Sketchbook from research trips around Virginia. Has many pages torn out and perhaps relocated elsewhere in the collection.
  - Notebook 24, 60 pages (29 cm) (Volume 3)
    Research reference organized alphebetically.
  - Notebook 5 1923, 34 pages (Volume 4)
    Sketchbook from student trip to Europe, mostly empty.
  - Notebook 7 1923, 137 pages (18 cm) (Volume 5)
    Notes and sketches from student trip to Venice.
  - Notebook 16, 144 pages (20 cm) (Volume 6)
    Contains miscellaneous sketches, mostly empty.
  - Notebook 14, 182 pages (22 cm) (Volume 7)
    Reference books listed alphabetically by title. Binding separated from leaves.
  - Notebook 8, 64 pages (20 cm) (Volume 8)
    Sketches of church architectural details. Has multiple sketches inserted in volume.
  - Notebook 11, 158 pages (16 cm) (Volume 9)
    Sketches of architectural details such as mosaics and brick work. Not exclusively in the colonial style so it is likely the notebook is from before Moorehead started working on the Restoration of Colonial Williamsburg.
  - Notebook 9, 116 pages (19 cm) (Volume 10)
    Contains in depth notes on architectural details. Likely from when Moorehead was a student at Harvard.
  - S Moorehead Personal, 80 pages (26 cm) (Volume 11)
    Notes on Colonial Buildings in Williamsburg listed alphabetically by name. Also contains list of 17th-18th century British Monarchs.
  - Notebook 4 circa 1920s, 150 pages (20 cm) (Volume 12)
    Notes and sketches from Italy and France, from Moorehead's trip there as a student. Many pages clipped or removed entirely.
  - Notebook 1, 134 pages (30cm) (Volume 13)
    Contains sketches of architectural details from various Colonial building in Williamsburg, such as the Galt and Bell houses. Features primarily millwork. The binding is in poor condition and many leaves are removed from the volume.
  - Notebook 10 Circa 1920s, 82 pages (18 cm) (Volume 14)
    Notes and sketches from student trip to Italy and France, particularly on column type.
  - Notebook 15 1948, 60 pages (21 cm) (Volume 15)
    Reference sketches and notes on a brass canon from New Hampshire.
  - Notebook 12, 122 pages (27 cm) (Volume 16)
    Sketches of architectural details and floorplans from various Colonial buildings in Williamsburg. Has typed procedure on restoring a house glued to inside front board.
  - Notebook 21, 144 pages (25 cm) (Volume 17)
    Reference sketches and notes on various Colonial houses around Virginia with a list of reference books and photographs. Many leaves removed from volume.
  - Notebook 20, 152 pages (25 cm) (Volume 18)
    Sketches and notes on architectural details. Many leaves removed from volume.
  - Notebook 23, 118 pages (15 cm) (Volume 19)
    Notes on 18th century British Monarches and Govenors of Virginia. As well as a list of colonial buildings arranged alphabetically by location name
  - Notebook 13 1929, 198 pages (17 cm) (Volume 20)
    An account book in which Moorehead kept track of various projects he did in Williamsburg. Not comprehensive.
  - Notebook 6, 120 pages (15 cm) (Volume 21)
    Sketches mounted into album. Labeled ARCH 4a and arranged by architectural feature type.
  - Notebook 2 1923, 92 pages (23 cm) (Volume 22)
    Notes and sketches on architecture, likely from when Moorehead was a student.
  - Notebook 18, 94 pages (21 cm) (Volume 23)
    Notes on 17th century theaters.
  - Notebook 3 1923, 124 pages (20 cm) (Volume 24)